Will Gallia

Contact wgallia@gmail.com

http://wgallia.com +447944137483 29 Benyon Wharf 295 Kingsland Road E8 4DQ

PROFILE

I am a 23 year programmer living in London. I was brought up in Turkey, schooled in Bristol and spent a year in Manchester before coming to London, where I pursued an education in Computing, focusing on the creative possibilities of programming.

EXPERIENCE

Goldsmiths College, London

Lab Assistant

02.2013 - Present

I was invited to return to Goldsmiths to assist in the 1st year programming labs, where the students are taught Java in the Processing environment.

Matt Watkins Design, London

iOS Programmer

05.2012 - 10.2012

I was the sole developer for Wrfel-Mosaik, a digital version of the classic Swiss children's game of the same name.

Hellicar & Lewis, London

Computer Programmer

06.2012 - 08.2012

I worked in a team of three developers creating Triptych, a set of interactive installations showcasing Intel's new range of processors. Interaction was through a Microsoft Kinect sensor and large projections. The projects were programmed in C++ & GLSL and used openFrameworks.

Swanlea School, Whitechapel, London

Assistant Teacher

03.2011 - 04.2011

As part of the TDAs Student Associate scheme, I worked along side teachers in both the Science and Maths departments.

greyworld, London

Computer Programmer

07.2010 - 09.2010

As a summer job, I programmed real-time generative visuals for London based art collective greyworld. During this project I worked alongside greyworld's founder, Andrew Shoben and advertising agency Ogilvy, programming their ideas.

Dursley Swimming Pool and Sports Centre, Gloucestershire

Lifeguard

07.2007 - 01.2008

Capone's Nightclub, Dursley, Gloucestershire

Bartender

07.2007 - 07.2008

EDUCATION Imperial College, London

MSc Computing

10.2012 - Present

Goldsmiths College, London

BSc Creative Computing

09.2009 - 05.2012

First Class Honours

Awarded Undergraduate Prize

Clifton College, Bristol

Peter Brook (All Round) Scholarship

09.2002 - 06.2007

A-Level: Maths: A, Physics: A, Chemistry: B

GCSE: 4 A*, 5 A, 2 B

Skills Computer Programming

I have experience programming in a number of languages and environments. At University I program in Java, C, C++ and GNU Octave for projects ranging from multi-threaded servers to computer vision to digital signal processing. Outside of University, I work on websites and other projects using languages such as Python, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL.

I have great experience working with graphical languages such as Processing, and libraries such as openFrameworks as well as OpenGL and GLSL.

System Admistration

I run a Linux webserver and host websites for myself and friends, through this I am very comfortable in the UNIX shell and emacs editor.

Graphic Design

I have many years of experience with Adobe tools such as Photoshop and Illustrator. I can also comfortable in 3D environments such as Blender.

RECENT WORK

Visualising the London Underground

For a project in a graphics course at Univeristy, I visualised real Underground journeys published by Transport for London. I programmed this in OpenGL, where every journey was stored as a pixel in a buffer object and transformations were applied by the GPU using GLSL.

Fabricate

Fabricate, which is running my personal website, creates dynamic websites from text files, where 100% of the content is generated on the client side. Features include navigation via a command line and automatic pushing of content. It was made using JavaScript, Python and shell scripts.

Pedro & Sybil

For a second year project at University, I built and programmed a plotter (Pedro) and also wrote an accompanying piece of software to control it (Sybil). Full details, images, videos and code can be seen at: pedroandsybil.com. The plotter is controlled via a USB port on a laptop, where users can preview and manipulate the text/images before they are drawn. The software is native Mac OS X application programmed in C++/Objective-C using Cocoa and openFrameworks. The plotters firmware is programmed directly in C. All source code is open.

I recently won the first prize in the Goldsmiths Computing department art competition, my entry can be seen at wgallia.com#!adventuresinsine.

REFERENCES

Dr. Mick Grierson, Tutor: m.grierson@gold.ac.uk

Matt Watkins: matt@hofv.com